<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-09-13T14:13:09+01:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Arrival</title><link href="/2019/09/13/arrival.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Arrival" /><published>2019-09-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-09-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2019/09/13/arrival</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/09/13/arrival.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;touchdown&quot;&gt;Touchdown&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and so it begins. What I am sure will be a tumultuous two years (for now) at the University of Oxford.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Touchdown</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Facebook</title><link href="/2019/09/05/facebook.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Facebook" /><published>2019-09-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-09-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2019/09/05/facebook</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/09/05/facebook.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;facebook-has-another-privacy-breach&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/04/facebook-phone-numbers-exposed/&quot;&gt;Facebook has another Privacy Breach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another day, another Facebook user data and privacy breach. From the techcrunch article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The exposed server contained more than 419 million records over several databases on users across geographies, including 133 million records on U.S.-based Facebook users, 18 million records of users in the U.K., and another with more than 50 million records on users in Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But because the server wasn’t protected with a password, anyone could find and access the database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is getting absolutely ridiculous. You would have to be insane to trust Facebook with any of your private data, let alone a hotdog stand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, just to remind you all: Facebook owns Instagram and Whatsapp too. Whatever data you have on those platforms isn’t safe either.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Facebook has another Privacy Breach</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tminus10</title><link href="/2019/09/02/tminus10.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tminus10" /><published>2019-09-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-09-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2019/09/02/tminus10</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/09/02/tminus10.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;t-minus-10&quot;&gt;T-Minus 10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10 days to go before I leave Japan for the UK. My gosh, time flies. Sometimes I still struggle to believe that I’ve been in Japan for this long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perth, and the suburbs of Joondalup and Clarkson, seem so far away now…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have little idea where I’ll end up after the UK. When I’m asked where I plan on being after the UK I usually answer:
“Hopefully somewhere interesting, or a place where I’m happy.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">T-Minus 10</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hongkong</title><link href="/2019/08/16/hongkong.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hongkong" /><published>2019-08-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2019/08/16/hongkong</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/08/16/hongkong.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-fate-of-hong-kong&quot;&gt;The Fate of Hong Kong&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I await to board a flight to Hong Kong, I wonder how the situation escalated so acutely in such a short amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong was perhaps fated to this collision course ever since the days of empire, after it was taken by the British. After that, the British faced a situation of “damned if you, damned if you don’t” when it came to deciding Hong Kong’s sovereignty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 20/20 hindsight it’s easy to criticise the British decision to annex Hong Kong to the PRC. At the time, however, it seemed like the sensible thing to do. The PRC had adopted its “two systems one country” rule under the Deng Xiaoping, and China was an up and coming superpower. There was also hope and optimism that China would soften its stance towards its citizens, and expand their civil rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, then again, one could’ve lashed out against the British decision citing Tiananmen Square as a prime example of China saying one thing but doing another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever the case may be, the people of Hong Kong, and the international community, must come to accept the 1997 annexation. But, China should be held responsible for overreaching and violating its “two system one country” promise. There is very little doubt that the controversial extradition bill was the spark that blew the TNT on this entire situation. That was clearly wrong, and could only come across as disingenuous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, calm heads will prevail.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Fate of Hong Kong</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Facebook</title><link href="/2019/08/14/facebook.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Facebook" /><published>2019-08-14T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2019/08/14/facebook</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/08/14/facebook.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;facebook-listens-to-and-transcribes-your-messenger-calls&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-08-13/facebook-paid-hundreds-of-contractors-to-transcribe-users-audio&quot;&gt;Facebook Listens to and Transcribes your Messenger Calls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In news that is surprising to nobody, Bloomberg reports that Facebook has been hiring external contractors to listen to and transcribe private conversations on its popular Messenger app. Facebook defends its actions by saying that companies such as Amazon, Apple, and Google do the same thing. Unfortunately for Facebook and Zuckerberg, things are not that simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent report from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/jul/26/apple-contractors-regularly-hear-confidential-details-on-siri-recordings&quot;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt; revealed that Apple listened to a small sample of audio recordings; but only of customers interacting with Siri. Google too was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/20/17594802/google-home-how-to-delete-conversations-recorded&quot;&gt;caught red handed&lt;/a&gt; recording Google Home and “OK Google!” interactions, and at a much larger scale than what Apple did with Siri. Amazon was the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/3/7/17092334/amazon-alexa-devices-strange-laughter&quot;&gt;worst offender&lt;/a&gt;, as it was revealed that its Echo speakers consistently listened to everything users said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, there is still a big difference between Facebook, and Amazon, Apple, and Google. The latter used voice recordings of customers interacting with their AI voice assistants, while Facebook actually listens to your private conversations with other people. It’s actually a pretty stark difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just another reason, on an ever growing list, to take digital privacy seriously.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Facebook Listens to and Transcribes your Messenger Calls</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Oxford</title><link href="/2019/08/07/oxford.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oxford" /><published>2019-08-07T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2019/08/07/oxford</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/08/07/oxford.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;to-the-next-adventure&quot;&gt;To the Next Adventure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It brings me great pleasure to belatedly announce to my dear friends and family, that I have been officially accepted as a graduate student into the University of Oxford. I will begin my studies at Oxford this September, with a Master of Philosophy (MPhil) in economics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To say that this has been a long time coming would be an understatement. This announcement marks the achievement of a dream and goal that began over six years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, and most importantly, being accepted into Oxford is not due to the efforts of me alone. I cannot stress this enough. I was well and truly supported, motivated, inspired, mentored, and challenged to get this far. The list of people who I wish to extend my most sincere thanks and appreciation is long. Chances are, if you’re reading this, you are one of the people I wish to thank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my amazing friends and family I grew up with, laughed with, worked with, and studied with in Perth, Osaka, Canberra, and Tokyo: &lt;strong&gt;Thank you!&lt;/strong&gt; Thank you so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More recently, I wish to express my most sincere gratitude to Professor Ippei Fujiwara. One of the most dedicated, passionate, sharpest and brightest individuals I’ve ever had the privilege of working with. I hope to continue his legacy and passion for research, teaching, and desire for knowledge. I’ve got big shoes to fill, but I approach the challenge with enthusiasm and boundless optimism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, it is also imperative to keep in mind that this is just another step – another journey – in the adventure of life. I look forward to discovering, learning, and achieving even bigger and better things – with all your support. I am absolutely certain that there will be good times and bad times. Times where I will fall, fail, and make mistakes. I ask that you continue to tolerate, teach, and help me with whatever comes next, together.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">To the Next Adventure</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hiroshima</title><link href="/2019/08/06/hiroshima.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hiroshima" /><published>2019-08-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2019/08/06/hiroshima</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/08/06/hiroshima.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;todays-the-day&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hpmmuseum.jp/?lang=eng&quot;&gt;Today’s the Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today marks 74 years since the bombing of Hiroshima. The first – and, tragically, not the last – time nuclear weapons were willingly dropped on a civilian population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no justification for the mass murder of innocent civilians. Anyone attempting to do so is either an idiot or heinously evil.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Today’s the Day</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Intelsunnycove</title><link href="/2019/07/31/intelsunnycove.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intelsunnycove" /><published>2019-07-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2019/07/31/intelsunnycove</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/31/intelsunnycove.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;intels-new-𝛍arch&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/14514/examining-intels-ice-lake-microarchitecture-and-sunny-cove&quot;&gt;Intel’s New 𝛍arch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a change of pace, rather than talking about Apple, let’s talk about Intel (oh boy…). As many who have been following PC hardware recently would know, Intel has been struggling. They’ve been stuck on their 14nm process for years, their Skylake architecture is looking very long in the tooth, their consumer lineup is a horrible mess, AMD has become a very real threat in enterprise and server markets, and x86’s future remains as uncertain as ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, however, believe that Intel will make a strong turnaround next year. This will be spearheaded by &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.intel.com/biography/raja-m-koduri/#gs.ta1ti3&quot;&gt;Raja Koduri&lt;/a&gt; leading Intel’s GPU technology efforts, and semiconductor architect superstar &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/13048/an-anandtech-exclusive-the-jim-keller-interview&quot;&gt;Jim Keller&lt;/a&gt; joining the fray too. I anticipate big and significant announcements from Koduri and Keller, who have pulled off miracle after miracle everywhere they’ve been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, more immediate than whatever projects Koduri and Keller are working on, is the upcoming introduction and launch of Intel’s new CPU microarchitecture. At long last, Skylake has a successor – one that will also come out on Intel’s perhaps still janky 10nm process. Say hello to Sunny Cove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://hirothreading.github.io/thehonourroll//assets/images/intelsunnycove.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Intel's Sunny Cove microarchitecture&quot; height=&quot;200px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anandtech has prepared a fantastic &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/14514/examining-intels-ice-lake-microarchitecture-and-sunny-cove&quot;&gt;deep dive&lt;/a&gt; on Sunny Cove. If you have a free afternoon, I definitely recommend taking a good read. According to this Anandtech report, Intel has rejigged their CPU architecture in dramatic fashion – perhaps as big of a change since the Nehalem to Sandy Bridge transition!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Intel can deliver on all their promises, then we’re looking at some significant performance, power efficiency, and platform/package efficiency gains. Average instruction per-clock gains are predicted to be roughly 18% over Skylake, on-die integration of Thunderbolt 3 (and hence a doubling of PCIe lanes from the CPU die), a revamped cache and memory controller system, and a large increase in GPU resources all point toward a very impressive new architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is, of course, if Intel can deliver on these promises…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Intel’s New 𝛍arch</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Appleq3results</title><link href="/2019/07/31/appleq3results.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Appleq3results" /><published>2019-07-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2019/07/31/appleq3results</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/31/appleq3results.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;apples-2019-q3-financial-results&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/07/apple-reports-third-quarter-results/&quot;&gt;Apple’s 2019 Q3 Financial Results&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sheer scale and strength of this company never ceases to amaze me. Here are the headline figures: $53.8 billion in revenue, $10 billion in net profit, and 37.6% gross margin just for this quarter alone. This is roughly a one per cent increase over the previous year-ago quarter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These figures are being driven on the back of Mac revenue increasing 11% YoY, iPad revenue up 8% YoY, Services up 13% YoY, and &lt;strong&gt;Wearables up 68% YoY&lt;/strong&gt;. I can only see these figures increasing over the coming year, as Apple continues to fill out these categories with some interesting products such as the new Mac Pro and MacBook Pros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, &lt;a href=&quot;https://sixcolors.com/post/2019/07/apple-third-quarter-2019-results-and-charts/&quot;&gt;Jason Snell&lt;/a&gt;  over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://sixcolors.com&quot;&gt;sixcolors&lt;/a&gt; has a great graphical representation and breakdown of Apple’s results. Check it out if you have time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Apple’s 2019 Q3 Financial Results</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Applebuysintelmodem</title><link href="/2019/07/26/applebuysintelmodem.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Applebuysintelmodem" /><published>2019-07-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2019/07/26/applebuysintelmodem</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/26/applebuysintelmodem.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;apple-purchases-intels-modem-business&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/07/apple-to-acquire-the-majority-of-intels-smartphone-modem-business/&quot;&gt;Apple Purchases Intel’s Modem Business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add this to the list of things I thought would happen. This is another natural progression of Apple’s – and perhaps more specifically, Tim Cook’s – approach to its platforms and devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Johny Srouji, Apple’s senior vice president of Hardware Technologies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We’ve worked with Intel for many years and know this team shares Apple’s passion for designing technologies that deliver the world’s best experiences for our users. Apple is excited to have so many excellent engineers join our growing cellular technologies group, and know they’ll thrive in Apple’s creative and dynamic environment. They, together with our significant acquisition of innovative IP, will help expedite our development on future products and allow Apple to further differentiate moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With full control over the CPU, GPU, and now, cellular modem, this will allow Apple to further increase their already dominant lead in hardware performance and efficiency on their devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s been a lot of talk in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/14676/apple-to-buy-bulk-of-intels-smartphone-modem-business&quot;&gt;tech media&lt;/a&gt; about how this Intel deal will affect Apple’s 2020 (and beyond) iPhones – particularly iPhone’s 5G capabilities.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I think a lot of pundits are missing another key opportunity that this buyout presents Apple: the opportunity to miniaturise cellular modems for ultraportable devices and wearables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While iPhone will be the short term benefactor of this deal, I think the bigger winners amongst Apple’s devices and platforms will be the Apple Watch, AirPods, and perhaps other future yet-to-be-announced wearable devices. The Mac and iPad will also benefit from Apple’s in-house modems, but to lesser extent as they’re nowhere near as thermally or physically limited as the iPhone and Apple Watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also believe that this won’t be the last we hear of Apple’s desire to control more of the components in its devices. For example, we know that Apple is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-03-19/apple-is-said-to-develop-displays-to-replace-samsung-screens&quot;&gt;developing MicroLED technology&lt;/a&gt;, with potentially significant benefits across all of its hardware platforms. Phil Schiller has also talked about how important camera technology is to iPhone, and how he views iPhone as the modern-day replacement to the point-and-shoot camera. So we may see Apple make further aggressive moves in the areas of camera technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, this Apple-Intel deal will be a boon to Apple – and, more importantly, to Apple’s customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tomsguide.com/opinion/heres-why-apple-is-spending-dollar1-billion-to-buy-intels-modems&quot;&gt;Jason Snell&lt;/a&gt; has an excellent write up covering the Apple-Intel deal over at Tom’s Guide. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Apple Purchases Intel’s Modem Business</summary></entry></feed>