<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-01T00:04:28+09:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Intelsunnycove</title><link href="/2019/07/31/intelsunnycove.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intelsunnycove" /><published>2019-07-31T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-31T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/31/intelsunnycove</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/31/intelsunnycove.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;intels-new-𝛍arch&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/14514/examining-intels-ice-lake-microarchitecture-and-sunny-cove&quot;&gt;Intel’s New 𝛍arch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a change of pace, rather than talking about Apple, let’s talk about Intel (oh boy…). As many who have been following PC hardware recently would know, Intel has been struggling. They’ve been stuck on their 14nm process for years, their Skylake architecture is looking very long in the tooth, their consumer lineup is a horrible mess, AMD has become a very real threat in enterprise and server markets, and x86’s future remains as uncertain as ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, however, believe that Intel will make a strong turnaround next year. This will be spearheaded by &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.intel.com/biography/raja-m-koduri/#gs.ta1ti3&quot;&gt;Raja Koduri&lt;/a&gt; leading Intel’s GPU technology efforts, and semiconductor architect superstar &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/13048/an-anandtech-exclusive-the-jim-keller-interview&quot;&gt;Jim Keller&lt;/a&gt; joining the fray too. I anticipate big and significant announcements from Koduri and Keller, who have pulled off miracle after miracle everywhere they’ve been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, more immediate than whatever projects Koduri and Keller are working on, is the upcoming introduction and launch of Intel’s new CPU microarchitecture. At long last, Skylake has a successor – one that will also come out on Intel’s perhaps still janky 10nm process. Say hello to Sunny Cove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/intelsunnycove.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Intel's Sunny Cove microarchitecture&quot; title=&quot;Intel's Sunny Cove Microarchitecture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anandtech has prepare a fantastic &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/14514/examining-intels-ice-lake-microarchitecture-and-sunny-cove&quot;&gt;deep dive&lt;/a&gt; on Sunny Cove. If you have a free afternoon, I definitely recommend taking a good read. According to this Anandtech report, Intel has rejigged their CPU architecture in dramatic fashion – perhaps as big of a change since the Nehalem to Sandy Bridge transition!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Intel can deliver on all their promises, then we’re looking at some significant performance, power efficiency, and platform/package efficiency gains. Average instruction per-clock gains are predicted to be roughly 18% over Skylake, on-die integration of Thunderbolt 3 (and hence a doubling of PCIe lanes from the CPU die), a revamped cache and memory controller system, and a large increase in GPU resources all point toward a very impressive new architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is, of course, if Intel can deliver on these promises…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Intel’s New 𝛍arch</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Appleq3results</title><link href="/2019/07/31/appleq3results.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Appleq3results" /><published>2019-07-31T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-31T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/31/appleq3results</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/31/appleq3results.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;apples-2019-q3-financial-results&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/07/apple-reports-third-quarter-results/&quot;&gt;Apple’s 2019 Q3 Financial Results&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sheer scale and strength of this company never ceases to amaze me. Here are the headline figures: $53.8 billion in revenue, $10 billion in net profit, and 37.6% gross margin just for this quarter alone. This is roughly a one per cent increase over the previous year-ago quarter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These figures are being driven on the back of Mac revenue increasing 11% YoY, iPad revenue up 8% YoY, Services up 13% YoY, and &lt;strong&gt;Wearables up 68% YoY&lt;/strong&gt;. I can only see these figures increasing over the coming year, as Apple continues to fill out these categories with some interesting products such as the new Mac Pro and MacBook Pros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, &lt;a href=&quot;https://sixcolors.com/post/2019/07/apple-third-quarter-2019-results-and-charts/&quot;&gt;Jason Snell&lt;/a&gt;  over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://sixcolors.com&quot;&gt;sixcolors&lt;/a&gt; has a great graphical representation and breakdown of Apple’s results. Check it out if you have time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Apple’s 2019 Q3 Financial Results</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Applebuysintelmodem</title><link href="/2019/07/26/applebuysintelmodem.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Applebuysintelmodem" /><published>2019-07-26T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-26T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/26/applebuysintelmodem</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/26/applebuysintelmodem.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;apple-purchases-intels-modem-business&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/07/apple-to-acquire-the-majority-of-intels-smartphone-modem-business/&quot;&gt;Apple Purchases Intel’s Modem Business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add this to the list of things I thought would happen. This is another natural progression of Apple’s – and perhaps more specifically, Tim Cook’s – approach to its platforms and devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Johny Srouji, Apple’s senior vice president of Hardware Technologies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We’ve worked with Intel for many years and know this team shares Apple’s passion for designing technologies that deliver the world’s best experiences for our users. Apple is excited to have so many excellent engineers join our growing cellular technologies group, and know they’ll thrive in Apple’s creative and dynamic environment. They, together with our significant acquisition of innovative IP, will help expedite our development on future products and allow Apple to further differentiate moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With full control over the CPU, GPU, and now, cellular modem, this will allow Apple to further increase their already dominant lead in hardware performance and efficiency on their devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s been a lot of talk in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/14676/apple-to-buy-bulk-of-intels-smartphone-modem-business&quot;&gt;tech media&lt;/a&gt; about how this Intel deal will affect Apple’s 2020 (and beyond) iPhones – particularly iPhone’s 5G capabilities.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I think a lot of pundits are missing another key opportunity that this buyout presents Apple: the opportunity to miniaturise cellular modems for ultraportable devices and wearables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While iPhone will be the short term benefactor of this deal, I think the bigger winners amongst Apple’s devices and platforms will be the Apple Watch, AirPods, and perhaps other future yet-to-be-announced wearable devices. The Mac and iPad will also benefit from Apple’s in-house modems, but to lesser extent as they’re nowhere near as thermally or physically limited as the iPhone and Apple Watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also believe that this won’t be the last we hear of Apple’s desire to control more of the components in its devices. For example, we know that Apple is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-03-19/apple-is-said-to-develop-displays-to-replace-samsung-screens&quot;&gt;developing MicroLED technology&lt;/a&gt;, with potentially significant benefits across all of its hardware platforms. Phil Schiller has also talked about how important camera technology is to iPhone, and how he views iPhone as the modern-day replacement to the point-and-shoot camera. So we may see Apple make further aggressive moves in the areas of camera technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, this Apple-Intel deal will be a boon to Apple – and, more importantly, to Apple’s customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tomsguide.com/opinion/heres-why-apple-is-spending-dollar1-billion-to-buy-intels-modems&quot;&gt;Jason Snell&lt;/a&gt; has an excellent write up covering the Apple-Intel deal over at Tom’s Guide. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Apple Purchases Intel’s Modem Business</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Japansecretshame</title><link href="/2019/07/24/japansecretshame.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Japansecretshame" /><published>2019-07-24T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-24T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/24/japansecretshame</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/24/japansecretshame.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;japans-secret-shame-and-the-courage-of-shiori-ito&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/29/world/asia/japan-rape.html&quot;&gt;Japan’s Secret Shame and the Courage of Shiori Ito&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month I was invited to a public screening of the BBC produced documentary, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/articles/3z44Njyr5wzm3wbVMGZ7tFr/shiori-ito-japan-s-attitudes-to-allegations-of-sexual-violence-are-locked-in-the-past?fbclid=IwAR0_v4FXCMuaBYGNg_t5KbYoBUisaqSjWbFX7SmpyOonLtqgfEhU6x0fT54&quot;&gt;Japan’s Secret Shame&lt;/a&gt;. The screening was organised by &lt;a href=&quot;https://telljp.com/?fbclid=IwAR1rAFC4EUCMwhf92pCQ2Qsp7AcwL915fXOhw6SAUXvAuLTpEQ0tE0YxL1g&quot;&gt;tell Japan&lt;/a&gt;, an organisation dedicated to counselling and raising awareness around mental health issues in Japan. They’re a fantastic organisation, and I recommend everyone to check them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Japan’s Secret Shame tells the story of Shiori Ito, a former journalism student who was studying in New York with ambitions to return to Japan to start her career. While in New York she met Noriyuki Yamaguchi, a senior journalist from broadcaster TBS Japan. Mr Yamaguchi made an informal promise to Ms Ito that he would help with her career once her studies were complete in New York, and after she returned back to Tokyo. Ms Ito, like any enthusiastic young person willing to make their mark on the world, took Mr Yamaguchi up on his offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ms Ito returned to Tokyo once her studies were finished, and she met Mr Yamaguchi in person over dinner. Mr Yamaguchi had other plans for their encounter however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ms Ito alleges that Mr Yamaguchi drugged and raped her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether or not you believe Ms Ito’s account of events is one thing — the documentary isn’t concerned about that. What the documentary highlights is Japan’s ridiculously archaic and barbaric legal system, completely inept and unable to support victims of sexual violence — whether it be women, men, or — tragically — children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, the documentary shines a spotlight on the disgusting and idiotic views of politicians such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.japantimes.co.jp/news/2018/09/05/national/lgbt-politicians-condemn-diet-members-slur-lgbt-couples-ask-abe/#.XTg4ri1L3UI&quot;&gt;Mio Sugita&lt;/a&gt; and other media shock jocks, who have done nothing but condemn Ms Ito and the thousands of other Japanese women each year who are brave enough to speak out against rape and sexual violence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I strongly urge you all, if you have a spare hour, to watch Japan’s Secret Shame. It’s not an easy watch, but it is extremely informative and of critical importance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I viewed it at a public screening, and witnessed the impact it had on the audience. As I turned to the rest of audience after the screening, I noticed that dozens of women were left with hands over their mouths and with tears in their eyes. No doubt this issue — this injustice — hit close to home for many.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Japan’s Secret Shame and the Courage of Shiori Ito</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stevejobs</title><link href="/2019/07/20/stevejobs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stevejobs" /><published>2019-07-20T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-20T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/20/stevejobs</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/20/stevejobs.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;steve-jobs-on-rupert-murdoch-and-fox-news--2010&quot;&gt;Steve Jobs on Rupert Murdoch and Fox News  (2010)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that I am a huge fan of Steve Jobs, and believe that his insights into the tech industry and culture were absolutely brilliant. Here is one of his lesser known quotes that remains as one of my favourites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The axis today is not liberal and conservative, the axis is constructive-destructive, and you’ve cast your lot with the destructive people. Fox has become an incredibly destructive force in our society. You can be better, and this is going to be your legacy if you’re not careful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Steve Jobs on Rupert Murdoch and Fox News (2010)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Semiconductors</title><link href="/2019/07/16/semiconductors.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Semiconductors" /><published>2019-07-16T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-16T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/16/semiconductors</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/16/semiconductors.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-introduction-to-the-semiconductor-industry&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/8223/an-introduction-to-semiconductor-physics-technology-and-industry?fbclid=IwAR1g-nfpxIPwjx0edQYmRl3mv6psyFSliSx14WJ9x1qYMhENqRbkMSFULhE&quot;&gt;An Introduction to the Semiconductor Industry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An excellent introduction to semiconductors, CMOS design, and microprocessor architectures by Anandtech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun fact – and some of my friends know this – after entering university, I was so close to changing my major to electrical engineering. Having tinkered with PCs throughout high school, and being utterly obsessed with how companies like Intel, AMD, and Nvidia built and designed chip architectures such as NetBurst, Hammer, Conroe, R500, G80, R600, RV770, and so on. I wanted to become a semiconductor/chip architect myself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was around the time Apple was making its way into designing its own chips too. I recall there being news about how it was custom designing its own A4 System-on-Chip (SoC). The A4 was an amazing SoC, powering the high performance graphics of the iPhone 4’s Retina display. Apple continued hitting home runs with its custom chip adventures with the A5, A5X, A6, and all the way to today’s industry leading A12X Bionic SoC inside its iPad Pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This stuff fascinates me to this day. Intel’s venerable Skylake architecure (now very long in the tooth), AMD’s Zen 2 and Navi architectures, IBM’s POWER8, and Apple’s SoCs and platform controllers – all of it. I spend way too much reading it how these amazing pieces of technology are designed and built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back when I was an undergrad I decided to give up my dreams on becoming an electrical engineer and chip architect. I was told that I would need to study for at least a decade (B.Eng + M.Sc + PhD) to build up expertise in the area. Even then, I would have to go over the US, Japan, or Taiwan to find a job, and then I would have to compete against graduates from institutions such as CalTech, MIT, and Stanford. I decided that it was too long of a commitment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would, ironically, end up studying economics for over a decade!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">An Introduction to the Semiconductor Industry</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bingethinking</title><link href="/2019/07/15/bingethinking.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bingethinking" /><published>2019-07-15T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-15T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/15/bingethinking</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/15/bingethinking.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;binge-thinking-podcast-episode-26-economic-booms-and-busts&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bingethinkingpodcast.com/episodes/2018/2/27/episode-26-economic-booms-and-busts-with-david-murakami?fbclid=IwAR3KsopIrVunDbMvWkblbBTT45L7U7VFO2Q3LhICWAluPXVUeTGJvOZcqyA&quot;&gt;Binge Thinking Podcast Episode 26: Economic Booms and Busts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another gem I found on my Facebook page. My friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://bingethinkingpodcast.com/host&quot;&gt;Caspar Roxburgh&lt;/a&gt; hosts the Binge Thinking podcast:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;‘Binge Thinking’ is a conversation podcast for young intellectuals, activists or just interesting people. Guests share their thoughts on who they are, what they do, and how the modern world looks from their perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The show reveals millennial insights into industries, events, or debates. Listen to smart, funny, eccentric and sometimes outrageous guests you can relate to. If you will live through the next 50 years, hear about those that will be there too. We binge news and current affairs, working life, identity politics, political politics, personal philosophies, relationships and everything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough to be invited onto the podcast for its 26th episode back in February 2018. It was a huge blast, and hopefully I can make a return to Caspar’s show again.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Binge Thinking Podcast Episode 26: Economic Booms and Busts</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Theprophet</title><link href="/2019/07/14/theprophet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Theprophet" /><published>2019-07-14T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-14T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/14/theprophet</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/14/theprophet.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-prophet-by-kahlil-gibran&quot;&gt;“The Prophet” by Kahlil Gibran&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A beautiful quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Your joy is your sorrow unmasked.&lt;br /&gt;
And the selfsame well from which your laughter rises was oftentimes filled with your tears. And how else can it be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The deeper the sorrow that carved into your being, the more joy you can contain. Is not the cup that holds your wine the very cup that was burned in the potter’s oven?  And is not the lute that soothes your spirit the very wood that was hollowed with knives?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you are joyous, look deep into your heart and you shall find it is only that which has given you sorrow that is giving you joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you are sorrowful, look again in your heart, and you shall see that in truth you are weeping for that which has been your delight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Some of you say, “Joy is greater than sorrow,” and other say, “Nay, sorrow is the greater.”&lt;br /&gt;
But I say unto you, they are inseparable. Together they come, and when one sits alone with you at your board, remember that the other is asleep upon your bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Verily you are suspended like scales between your sorrow and your joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Only when you are empty are you at standstill and balanced.&lt;br /&gt;
When the treasure-keeper lifts you to weigh his gold and silver, needs must your joy or your sorrow rise or fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">“The Prophet” by Kahlil Gibran</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Twocheersforanarchy</title><link href="/2019/07/13/twocheersforanarchy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Twocheersforanarchy" /><published>2019-07-13T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/13/twocheersforanarchy</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/13/twocheersforanarchy.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;james-c-scott-two-cheers-for-anarchism&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://press.princeton.edu/titles/9816.html&quot;&gt;James C. Scott “Two Cheers for Anarchism”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably the most critical text from Scott’s fantastic book. Apologies for the long read, but it is well worth it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Public school was invented more or less at the same time as the large factory under a single roof, and the two institutions bear a strong family resemblance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The school was, in a sense, a factory for the basic training of the minimal skills of numeracy and literacy necessary for an industrialising society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Universal public education is, of course, designed to do far more than merely turn out the labour force required by industry. It is as much a political as an economic institution. It is designed to produce a patriotic citizen whose loyalty to the nation will trump regional and local identities of language, ethnicity and religion. The universal citizenship of revolutionary France had its counterpart in universal conscription. Manufacturing such patriotic citizens through the school system was accomplished less through the manifest curriculum than through its language of instruction, its standardisation and its implicit lessons in regimentation, authority and order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The modern primary and secondary school system has been much altered by changing theories of pedagogy and, most especially, by affluence and the “youth culture” itself. But there is no mistaking its origins in the factory, if not the prison. Compulsory universal education, however democratising in one sense, has also meant that, with few exceptions, the students have to be there. The fact that attendance is not a choice, not an autonomous act, means that it starts out fundamentally on the wrong foot as a compulsory institution, with all the alienation that this duress implies, especially as children grow older.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The great tragedy of the public school system, however, is that it is by and large, a one product factory. This tendency has only been exacerbated by the push in recent decades for standardisation, measurement, testing and accountability. The resulting incentives for students, teachers, principals and whole school districts have had the effect of bending all efforts toward fashioning a standard product that satisfies the criteria the auditors have established.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What is this product? It is a certain form of analytical intelligence, narrowly conceived, which can, it is assumed, be measured by tests. We know, of course, that there are many, many skills that valuable and important for a successful society that are not even remotely related to analytical intelligence, among them, artistic talent, imaginative intelligence, mechanical intelligence, musical and dance skills, creative intelligence, emotional intelligence, social skills and ethical intelligence. Some of these aptitudes find a place in extracurricular activities, especially in sports, but not in the measured and graded activities on which so much now depends for students, teachers and schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This monochromatic flattening of education is brought to a kind of apotheosis in educational systems like those in France, Japan, China and Korea, where the exercise culminates in a single examination on which one’s future mobility and life’s chances substantially depend. Here the scramble to get into the best-regarded schools, to find extra-hours tutoring, and to attend special exam-preparation cram courses reaches a fever pitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How ironic it is that I, who write this, and virtually anyone who reads it, are the beneficiaries, the victors, of this rat race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Those of us who “won” this race are the lifetime beneficiaries of opportunities and privileges that would not likely otherwise have come our way. We are also are likely to carry a lifetime sense of entitlement, superiority, accomplishment and self esteem that comes from this victory. Let us bracket, for the moment, the question of whether this dividend is justified and what it actually means in terms of our value to ourselves and others, and merely note that it represents a fund of social capital that adjusts the odds of financial and status mobility radically in our favour. This is a lifetime privilege extended to perhaps one-fifth at most of those the system turns out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And what of the rest? What of the, say, 80 percent who in effect lose the race? They carry less social capital; the odds are adjusted against them. Perhaps as important is the fact that they are likely to carry a lifelong sense of having been defeated, of being less valued, of thinking they are inferior and slow witted. This system effect further adjusts the odds against them. And yet, have we any rational reason to credit the judgements of a system that values such a narrow bandwidth of human talents and measures achievement within this band by the ability to sit successfully for an exam?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Those who do poorly on tests of analytical intelligence may be incredibly talented at one or more of the many forms of intelligence that are neither taught nor valued by the school system. What sort of a system is it that wastes these talents, that sends four-fifths of its students away with a permanent stigma in the eyes of society’s gatekeepers, and perhaps in their own eyes as well? Are the dubious benefits of the privileges and opportunities accorded a presumed “analytical intelligence elite” by this pedagogical tunnel vision worth so much social damage and waste?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food for thought.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">James C. Scott “Two Cheers for Anarchism”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Khanlabschool</title><link href="/2019/07/13/khanlabschool.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Khanlabschool" /><published>2019-07-13T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/13/khanlabschool</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/13/khanlabschool.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;salman-khan-rethinks-school&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://khanlabschool.org/wired&quot;&gt;Salman Khan Rethinks School&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My second post today on education and pedagogy. This article is a fairly old piece, but it is nonetheless a good read. I also recommend the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/sal_khan_let_s_teach_for_mastery_not_test_scores?language=en&quot;&gt;10-minute video available on TED&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Salman Khan Rethinks School</summary></entry></feed>