<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-12-22T22:09:49+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Economists</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/22/economists.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Economists" /><published>2019-12-22T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-12-22T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/12/22/economists</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/22/economists.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-changing-face-of-economics&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/dac3b1d8-20fc-11ea-b8a1-584213ee7b2b&quot;&gt;The Changing Face of Economics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interesting piece by the Financial Times on the evolution of economics over the past century. The article also highlights one of the main challenges of economics: Most people don’t know what economics is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In discussions with friends and colleagues at Oxford, most merely brushed off economics as being a derivative of politics. Some even accuse economics and economists as being partisan. For myself, and most other economists, there are few things more frustrating than being told this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Economics is a social science. Like the natural sciences, it can be used as a powerful tool, and it is badly misunderstood by those not well versed or practiced in it. The tragedy for economics is that it has a lot to say about things like money and wealth, which attracts a lot of unwanted attention from politics and those from other humanities disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Economics is a controversial discipline, and that is not likely to change. Whereas scientists only occasionally have to dip their toes into political waters such as climate change or vaccination, most of what economists study — from inequality to immigration, trade to taxation — lies squarely in the middle of the political battlefield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Still, some of us are doing our best, and all of us are human, as these portraits show. It is nice to be reminded of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Economics has a lot to say about a broad range of phenomena that we encounter on a day to day basis. It is the study of common sense and choice, and can help explain anything from dating, international trade, unemployment, black market activity, consumer satisfaction, negotiation, interest rates, and so much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Money, wealth, and political-economy, is but a tiny sliver of the discipline of economics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there’s a quote from Greg Mankiw’s essay &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.harvard.edu/files/mankiw/files/defending_the_one_percent_1.pdf&quot;&gt;“Defending the One Percent”&lt;/a&gt; which I quite like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;At the outset, it is worth noting that addressing the issue of rising inequality necessarily involves not just economics but also a healthy dose of political philosophy. We economists must recognize not only the limits of what we know about inequality’s causes, but also the limits on the ability of our discipline to prescribe policy responses. Economists who discuss policy responses to increasing inequality are often playing the role of amateur political philosopher (and, admittedly, I will do so in this essay). Given the topic, that is perhaps inevitable. But it is useful to keep in mind when we are writing as economists and when we are venturing beyond the boundaries of our professional expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversely, non-economists who discuss economics when considering policy responses to issues are playing with a tool that they may not fully comprehend. They need to be aware of the limits of their own understanding, but also to the limits that economics may have on any particular subject.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Changing Face of Economics</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Techfails</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/21/techfails.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Techfails" /><published>2019-12-21T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-12-21T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/12/21/techfails</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/21/techfails.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;84-of-the-biggest-tech-fails-of-the-decade&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/20/21029499/decade-fails-flops-tech-science-culture-apple-google-data-kickstarter-2010-2019&quot;&gt;84 of the Biggest Tech Fails of the Decade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great piece by The Verge which looks at some of the biggest fails and flops in the technology industry. A few things standout: Look at how many entries Google has on this list – a clear sign that the company lacks focus and vision (we can soon add Stadia to this list too); I would also add the 2013 Mac Pro and Apple’s neglect of the Mac platform for a good five years (although &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/mac/&quot;&gt;significant amendments&lt;/a&gt; have been made in the final year of the decade by Apple); and, the tech industry’s utter failure in protecting user privacy, and over-reliance on Chinese manufacturing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">84 of the Biggest Tech Fails of the Decade</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Michaelmasmadness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/20/michaelmasmadness.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Michaelmasmadness" /><published>2019-12-20T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-12-20T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/12/20/michaelmasmadness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/20/michaelmasmadness.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;michaelmas-madness-hopeful-hilary&quot;&gt;Michaelmas Madness, Hopeful Hilary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I provided an update. Apologies for that. This past week brought about the conclusion of the first trimester at the University of Oxford. For those unaware, Oxford has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ox.ac.uk/about/facts-and-figures/dates-of-term?wssl=1&quot;&gt;three trimesters&lt;/a&gt; each academic year: Michaelmas, Hilary, and Trinity. With the Michaelmas trimester over, I have a brief [desperately needed] winter break before the Hilary trimester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some reflection of my first trimester at Oxford is in order, I think. Where on earth do I begin? Michaelmas began with me in a bit of a funk, and facing some pretty challenging personal circumstances. Nevertheless, there was no time to stew or conduct too much introspection. I was blessed with an opportunity to rise up and meet the daunting task in front of me head on. To say that the programme at Oxford is mentally and physically draining would be an understatement. But it is strangely satisfying. It’s quite hard to describe the joy when you are able to complete or solve a complex mathematical problem at three o’clock in the morning in the college library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that note, I have been lucky to meet and make some fantastic new friends at Oxford. It truly is a blessing to have the chance to cross paths with amazingly talented people from all walks of life. Without them, there really would be no reprieve from the coursework, and meals would be no where near as enjoyable. And, of course, the dreaded problem sets are actually tolerable and somewhat exhilarating with good company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oxford, outside of the university, is a lovely quaint town. Initially it was jarring switching from Tokyo, but now that things have settled down, I find it quite nice. As you sit in one of Oxford’s libraries (my favourite is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radcliffe_Camera&quot;&gt;Radcliffe Camera&lt;/a&gt;), staring outside on a rainy day, it’s quite easy to forget about space and time. For a brief moment, all of the problems of the world disappear and fade away as you immerse yourself in the atmosphere and tranquility of your surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, there is London, which is fairly accessible from Oxford. It is complete mayhem and absolutely hectic. But I love it – and I can understand why so many other people do too. I’ve only been to London three times during this initial Michaelmas trimester. While there are certainly parallels with cities like Tokyo and Sydney, London, even at its heart, manages to retain many hidden gems and small boutique venues. The city is also home to a plethora of museums, historical sites, and the city has preserved a surprisingly large amount of parks and forestation. The end result is that one can always stumble upon something new during a walkabout in the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am now in Osaka, Japan, enjoying a very Autumn-like afternoon. I’ll be here until mid January, before I jet off to Perth. Osaka will always have a special place in my heart. It was my gateway to Japan, it was where I forged my adult identity, and it’s home to friends and relatives. Speaking of which, a couple of days ago I was blessed to catch up with a dear friend here. Despite having only a brief amount of time, it was a much needed nostalgic but refreshing occasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have said this many times before, but it’s worth repeating: Whatever successes or accomplishments I have and make are owed entirely to the amazing people that have helped, supported, and nurtured me. I stand on the shoulders of giants – family, friends, teachers, and mentors, people that I love, care for, and deeply respect. Compared to those that surround me, I am a mere fool with much to learn. I was pleasantly reminded of this during my catch up here in Osaka. I firmly believe that this world has a shortage of people with a keen and sharp eye for what is good and true – for people who take responsibility and ownership to make the world a better place than when they found it. I am indebted to good people like this to help their cause and do my best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that was Michaelmas in a nutshell. With my batteries recharged, confidence renewed, and a reminder for why I am where I am, I look forward to the Hilary trimester.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Michaelmas Madness, Hopeful Hilary</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Eafpiece</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/11/02/eafpiece.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Eafpiece" /><published>2019-11-02T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-11-02T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/11/02/eafpiece</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/11/02/eafpiece.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;japans-part-time-workers-need-tighter-reforms&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eastasiaforum.org/2019/11/02/japans-part-time-workers-need-tighter-reforms/&quot;&gt;Japan’s Part Time Workers Need Tighter Reforms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My recent piece published over at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eastasiaforum.org&quot;&gt;East Asia Forum&lt;/a&gt; on Japan’s labour challenges and the implications it may have on productivity, prices, and interest rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;wages and prices may rise if workers can remain productive well into their old age. But achieving this is no trivial task. Both public and private initiatives must be put in place to retrain and re-skill older workers. Where feasible and productive, allowing workers to continue full-time employment into their older years ought to be encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks go to the editorial team at the EAF for this piece.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Japan’s Part Time Workers Need Tighter Reforms</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Determinism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/12/determinism.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Determinism" /><published>2019-10-12T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-10-12T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/12/determinism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/12/determinism.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;determinism&quot;&gt;Determinism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever had a moment of apparent serendipity or bizarre coincidence – or series of these events – which just takes you aback, and makes you wonder if there is such a thing as fate or destiny?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, over a coffee with a few friends, I was discussing the idea or notion that none of us have true free will. The implications of this argument being true are quite significant. If we all follow some kind of deterministic path, then are some of us destined to be good and some of us bad?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, one could point out the mechanics of quantum physics as proof that, ultimately (albeit on the sub-atomic scale), nothing is determined – everything is random and probabilistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is perhaps, as usual, somewhere in the middle. We all have true free will, but in a sandbox. Where that sandbox is going, and just how far the parameters and boundary of the sandbox are, may be beyond the control of any individual.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Determinism</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">China</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/10/China.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="China" /><published>2019-10-10T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-10-10T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/10/China</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/10/China.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-much-is-it-worth-protecting-free-speech&quot;&gt;How Much is it Worth Protecting Free Speech?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh boy, where do we even begin with this one…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone is, I think, familiar with what is happening in Hong Kong: A poorly timed bill presented by the Hong Kong government was seen as capitulation and kowtowing to Beijing. The bill was a spark, and the general economic unrest and dissatisfaction by many young Hong Kong citizens was the fuel to this bonfire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we have two behemoth US corporations stuck in the crossfire: the NBA and Apple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the NBA: Houston Rockets General Manager, Daryl Morey, single handedly threw a multibillion dollar wrench into the NBA’s Chinese market expansion plans after he &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-49995985&quot;&gt;tweeted support for Hong Kong protestors&lt;/a&gt;. Morey’s tweet simply read the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Fight for freedom, stand with Hong Kong&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has since been deleted following a series of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sportingnews.com/us/nba/news/daryl-morey-hong-kong-tweet-china-nba-response-politicians/1dergufmvknmu1vdkm5t2x3pxn&quot;&gt;backflips and “no-comment” responses from NBA Commission Adam Silver&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://edition.cnn.com/2019/10/08/business/daryl-morey-tweet-nba-china/index.html&quot;&gt;withdrawal of billions of dollars of funding and sponsorship deals by Chinese Communist Party (CCP) backed organisations from the NBA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The situation is of course fully understandable, and both sides – the NBA and the CCP – are acting rationally. China is a growing market, many Chinese love basketball, and the CCP rules thought and online discussion with an iron fist to quell domestic political unrest. The NBA is a for-profit organisation, and it owes a duty to its shareholders and players to seek higher profits. There should be little wonder as to why ESPN has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://edition.cnn.com/2019/10/09/media/espn-daryl-morey-tweet-china/index.html&quot;&gt;completely silent&lt;/a&gt; on this issue – much to the frustration of US politicians and social commentary pundits. ESPN is of course owned by Disney, and Disney is desperate to keep reaping profits from the growing Chinese entertainment market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That brings us to Apple. The company has come under fire after it removed two apps – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/9/20907228/apple-quartz-app-store-china-removal-hong-kong-protests-censorship&quot;&gt;Quartz&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/10/09/technology/apple-hong-kong-app.html&quot;&gt;HKmap&lt;/a&gt; – from the App Store in Hong Kong and China. CEO &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/10/20908498/apple-ceo-tim-cook-hong-kong-protest-app-removed-store-email-employees-hkmaplive&quot;&gt;Tim Cook has come out defending Apple’s decision&lt;/a&gt;, stating:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The app in question allowed for the crowdsourced reporting and mapping of police checkpoints, protest hotspots, and other information,[…] On its own, this information is benign. However, over the past several days we received credible information, from the Hong Kong Cybersecurity and Technology Crime Bureau, as well as from users in Hong Kong, that the app was being used maliciously to target individual officers for violence and to victimize individuals and property where no police are present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read Cook’s full email in the links provided. I, however, am skeptical to his line of reasoning. As asked by John Gruber, there are three questions raised after reading Cook’s explanation:&lt;br /&gt;
1) When was HKmap.live “used maliciously to target individual officers for violence”?&lt;br /&gt;
2) When was it used to “victimize individuals and property where no police are present”?&lt;br /&gt;
3) What local laws in Hong Kong does it violate?
None of these questions have answers on the part of Cook or the Hong Kong authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, much like the NBA, Apple is acting rationally here. In fact, one could argue that Apple is even more dependant on China than the NBA is. However, and this may sound bizarre coming from an economist: is now the time for US corporations to be acting rationally?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a growing sense of resentment amongst many Americans – and generally in the West – toward US corporations bending and sacrificing their ethics in order to do business in China. (&lt;em&gt;Although, one could argue that these corporations never had ethics or morals in the first place&lt;/em&gt;) People are generally very good at spotting hypocrisy. When many major US corporations criticise President Donald Trump, decry racism, support minority communities such as the LGBT community, and proudly claim to be at the forefront of diversity movements, their deafening silence toward China’s constant human rights violations and abuses becomes so much more apparent. No matter which side of the debate you sit on, it’s hard to ignore the inconsistencies here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How this all plays out remains to be seen. Somewhat ironically, China’s desperation to silence discussion and debate over Hong Kong has only increased global coverage. So much so that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/10/10/business/china-blows-whistle-on-nationalist-protests-against-the-nba.html?smid=nytcore-ios-share&quot;&gt;CCP is now trying to calm domestic Chinese anger toward the NBA&lt;/a&gt;. China’s angst and dummyspit directed at the NBA has attracted the attention of NBA fans globally – many who had no idea what was happening in Hong Kong are now busy Googling and reading up on what all the fuss is about. To quote a certain Princess from Aladeraan:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The more you tighten your grip, the more systems will slip through your fingers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one more thing I want to say on this matter. What’s happening in Hong Kong (and West China, for that matter), and the entire dynamic between China and US corporations, affects us all. Going forward, as we all progress in our careers, many of you will have to ask yourself: how much is freedom worth? For how much money will you be willing to ignore the plight of people who have been oppressed by the CCP? For how much are you willing to be a hypocrite for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-7549977/Tiffany-removes-photo-Chinese-consumers-accused-jeweller-supporting-Hong-Kong-protests.html&quot;&gt;We can add Tiffany &amp;amp; Co to this mess.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">How Much is it Worth Protecting Free Speech?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Inequality</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/26/inequality.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Inequality" /><published>2019-09-26T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-09-26T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/09/26/inequality</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/26/inequality.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;unequal-we-stand&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/papers/w15483.pdf&quot;&gt;Unequal We Stand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate enough to attend the 5th Oxford – Federal Reserve Bank of New York – Bank of England monetary economics conference today. The keynote speech was delivered by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jonathanheathcote.com&quot;&gt;Jonathan Heathcote&lt;/a&gt;, who is a brilliant research economist at the Minneapolis Federal Reserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I don’t have access to his presentation slides, but his research showed a very clear and simple result: inequality in the United States is worsening, and it is potentially driven by cyclicality in the business cycle. We already know that recessions disproportionately affect the poor more so than the rich. However, Heathcote’s research connects recessions and downswings in the business cycle very convincingly to worsening income inequality in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put, according to Heathcote’s research, low skilled workers are particularly vulnerable to losing their jobs in a recession because of their substitutability, which in turn makes it more difficult for them to find employment even after a recession. As a double whammy, the economy takes a long time – a really long time – to recover from a recession and reach a stage where employment of low skilled workers recovers. The unfortunate effect of all this is that many low skilled workers enter long term unemployment, and even leave the labour force, further exacerbating the inequality problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those interested in the topic, I suggest reading Heathcote et al. (2009) (linked above), and waiting for Heathcote to release the new paper. His previous work was based on data prior to the global financial crisis (GFC). No doubt that the GFC has made this issue more prevalent than before.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Unequal We Stand</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Soseki</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/16/soseki.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Soseki" /><published>2019-09-16T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-09-16T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/09/16/soseki</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/16/soseki.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;natsume-soseki&quot;&gt;Natsume Soseki&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An insightful and somber quote from Japanese poet and novelist, Natsume Soseki (1867-1916):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You see, loneliness is the price we have to pay for being born in this modern age, so full of freedom, independence, and our own egoistical selves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Natsume Soseki</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Appledeepfusion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/13/appledeepfusion.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Appledeepfusion" /><published>2019-09-13T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-09-13T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/09/13/appledeepfusion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/13/appledeepfusion.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;apples-deep-fusion-technology&quot;&gt;Apple’s Deep Fusion Technology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Apple usually explains complicated technologies in a simple to understand manner – arguably the best in the industry – honestly, the 10 September event was confusing, light on details, and quite underwhelming. Exciting technologies such as the U1 chip, Deep Fusion, and SoC details [for Apple Watch Series 5] barely got any mention. There was way too much time dedicated to game demos, advertising videos, and speaker transitions. Not to mention a very head-tilting naming scheme for the new lineup of iPhones. &lt;em&gt;iPhone 11 Pro Max&lt;/em&gt;… really?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why not simply name the lineup: &lt;em&gt;iPhone 11&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;iPhone 11 Pro&lt;/em&gt;, and then differentiate the two Pro iPhones by size? This would at least bring some consistency between &lt;em&gt;iPhone Pro&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;MacBook Pro&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;iPad Pro&lt;/em&gt;. Heck, I’ve been hoping Apple would drop model numbers entirely and just refer to iPhones by their launch year. I think most people would agree that &lt;em&gt;iPhone Pro&lt;/em&gt; (2019, 6.5-inch) is a lot better than &lt;em&gt;iPhone 11 Pro Max&lt;/em&gt;. But anyway, my issues with Apple’s confusing naming scheme should be saved for another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this week’s keynote, Phil Schiller took stage to explain some of the secrets behind the iPhone 11’s camera technology. Of particular note and interest was Deep Fusion. Schiller’s explanation left a lot to be desired – and a lot to the imagination. Frustratingly, a lot of tech journalists have little idea what Deep Fusion is and have struggled to explain what the technology does. For example, this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/2019/09/10/apple-iphone-deep-fusion/&quot;&gt;engadget article&lt;/a&gt; says that Deep Fusion is Apple’s technology to tackle Google’s Night Sight. This is completely false. Apple will be employing Night Mode to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My understanding of Deep Fusion is that it is a machine learning (ML) based technology, powered by the A13 Bionic’s Neural Engine to replace or sidestep the camera’s image signalling processor (ISP) image capturing pipeline. My guess is that Deep Fusion only replaces the ISP’s duties for still photos, and that the ISP does most of the heavy lifting for other photo modes and video. When taking a photo, the A13 Bionic and iPhone’s camera lenses will basically take nine images: four short burst images taken before the user hits the photo button, four short burst images once the user hits the photo button, and a single long exposure image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The A13 Bionic’s Neural Engine will then analyse all nine images, applying various algorithms at the pixel and sub-pixel level to blend the images and combine them into a final image. The closest comparison I can think would be advanced anti-aliasing filtering techniques from the likes of AMD and Nvidia when it comes to 3D rendering pipelines. The key point is that the A13 Bionic determines how the final image is put together, pixel by pixel, rather than the camera ISP bluntly and broadly fusing multiple captured images. The technology is remarkable, and I’m just so surprised that Apple didn’t take more time to explain it further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure someone from the likes of Anandtech or Arstechnica will explore Deep Fusion soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Apple’s Deep Fusion Technology</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Arrival</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/13/arrival.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Arrival" /><published>2019-09-13T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-09-13T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/09/13/arrival</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/13/arrival.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;touchdown&quot;&gt;Touchdown&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and so it begins. What I am sure will be a tumultuous two years (for now) at the University of Oxford.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Touchdown</summary></entry></feed>