<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-15T16:11:47+09:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Bingethinking</title><link href="/2019/07/15/bingethinking.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bingethinking" /><published>2019-07-15T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-15T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/15/bingethinking</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/15/bingethinking.html">&lt;p&gt;##&lt;a href=&quot;https://bingethinkingpodcast.com/episodes/2018/2/27/episode-26-economic-booms-and-busts-with-david-murakami?fbclid=IwAR3KsopIrVunDbMvWkblbBTT45L7U7VFO2Q3LhICWAluPXVUeTGJvOZcqyA&quot;&gt;Binge Thinking Podcast Episode 26: Economic Booms and Busts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another gem I found on my Facebook page. My friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://bingethinkingpodcast.com/host&quot;&gt;Caspar Roxburgh&lt;/a&gt; hosts the Binge Thinking podcast:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;‘Binge Thinking’ is a conversation podcast for young intellectuals, activists or just interesting people. Guests share their thoughts on who they are, what they do, and how the modern world looks from their perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The show reveals millennial insights into industries, events, or debates. Listen to smart, funny, eccentric and sometimes outrageous guests you can relate to. If you will live through the next 50 years, hear about those that will be there too. We binge news and current affairs, working life, identity politics, political politics, personal philosophies, relationships and everything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough to be invited onto the podcast for its 26th episode back in February 2018. It was a huge blast, and hopefully I can make a return to Caspar’s show again.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">##Binge Thinking Podcast Episode 26: Economic Booms and Busts</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Theprophet</title><link href="/2019/07/14/theprophet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Theprophet" /><published>2019-07-14T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-14T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/14/theprophet</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/14/theprophet.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-prophet-by-kahlil-gibran&quot;&gt;“The Prophet” by Kahlil Gibran&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A beautiful quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Your joy is your sorrow unmasked.&lt;br /&gt;
And the selfsame well from which your laughter rises was oftentimes filled with your tears. And how else can it be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The deeper the sorrow that carved into your being, the more joy you can contain. Is not the cup that holds your wine the very cup that was burned in the potter’s oven?  And is not the lute that soothes your spirit the very wood that was hollowed with knives?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you are joyous, look deep into your heart and you shall find it is only that which has given you sorrow that is giving you joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you are sorrowful, look again in your heart, and you shall see that in truth you are weeping for that which has been your delight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Some of you say, “Joy is greater than sorrow,” and other say, “Nay, sorrow is the greater.”&lt;br /&gt;
But I say unto you, they are inseparable. Together they come, and when one sits alone with you at your board, remember that the other is asleep upon your bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Verily you are suspended like scales between your sorrow and your joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Only when you are empty are you at standstill and balanced.&lt;br /&gt;
When the treasure-keeper lifts you to weigh his gold and silver, needs must your joy or your sorrow rise or fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">“The Prophet” by Kahlil Gibran</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Twocheersforanarchy</title><link href="/2019/07/13/twocheersforanarchy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Twocheersforanarchy" /><published>2019-07-13T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/13/twocheersforanarchy</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/13/twocheersforanarchy.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;james-c-scott-two-cheers-for-anarchism&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://press.princeton.edu/titles/9816.html&quot;&gt;James C. Scott “Two Cheers for Anarchism”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably the most critical text from Scott’s fantastic book. Apologies for the long read, but it is well worth it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Public school was invented more or less at the same time as the large factory under a single roof, and the two institutions bear a strong family resemblance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The school was, in a sense, a factory for the basic training of the minimal skills of numeracy and literacy necessary for an industrialising society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Universal public education is, of course, designed to do far more than merely turn out the labour force required by industry. It is as much a political as an economic institution. It is designed to produce a patriotic citizen whose loyalty to the nation will trump regional and local identities of language, ethnicity and religion. The universal citizenship of revolutionary France had its counterpart in universal conscription. Manufacturing such patriotic citizens through the school system was accomplished less through the manifest curriculum than through its language of instruction, its standardisation and its implicit lessons in regimentation, authority and order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The modern primary and secondary school system has been much altered by changing theories of pedagogy and, most especially, by affluence and the “youth culture” itself. But there is no mistaking its origins in the factory, if not the prison. Compulsory universal education, however democratising in one sense, has also meant that, with few exceptions, the students have to be there. The fact that attendance is not a choice, not an autonomous act, means that it starts out fundamentally on the wrong foot as a compulsory institution, with all the alienation that this duress implies, especially as children grow older.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The great tragedy of the public school system, however, is that it is by and large, a one product factory. This tendency has only been exacerbated by the push in recent decades for standardisation, measurement, testing and accountability. The resulting incentives for students, teachers, principals and whole school districts have had the effect of bending all efforts toward fashioning a standard product that satisfies the criteria the auditors have established.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What is this product? It is a certain form of analytical intelligence, narrowly conceived, which can, it is assumed, be measured by tests. We know, of course, that there are many, many skills that valuable and important for a successful society that are not even remotely related to analytical intelligence, among them, artistic talent, imaginative intelligence, mechanical intelligence, musical and dance skills, creative intelligence, emotional intelligence, social skills and ethical intelligence. Some of these aptitudes find a place in extracurricular activities, especially in sports, but not in the measured and graded activities on which so much now depends for students, teachers and schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This monochromatic flattening of education is brought to a kind of apotheosis in educational systems like those in France, Japan, China and Korea, where the exercise culminates in a single examination on which one’s future mobility and life’s chances substantially depend. Here the scramble to get into the best-regarded schools, to find extra-hours tutoring, and to attend special exam-preparation cram courses reaches a fever pitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How ironic it is that I, who write this, and virtually anyone who reads it, are the beneficiaries, the victors, of this rat race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Those of us who “won” this race are the lifetime beneficiaries of opportunities and privileges that would not likely otherwise have come our way. We are also are likely to carry a lifetime sense of entitlement, superiority, accomplishment and self esteem that comes from this victory. Let us bracket, for the moment, the question of whether this dividend is justified and what it actually means in terms of our value to ourselves and others, and merely note that it represents a fund of social capital that adjusts the odds of financial and status mobility radically in our favour. This is a lifetime privilege extended to perhaps one-fifth at most of those the system turns out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And what of the rest? What of the, say, 80 percent who in effect lose the race? They carry less social capital; the odds are adjusted against them. Perhaps as important is the fact that they are likely to carry a lifelong sense of having been defeated, of being less valued, of thinking they are inferior and slow witted. This system effect further adjusts the odds against them. And yet, have we any rational reason to credit the judgements of a system that values such a narrow bandwidth of human talents and measures achievement within this band by the ability to sit successfully for an exam?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Those who do poorly on tests of analytical intelligence may be incredibly talented at one or more of the many forms of intelligence that are neither taught nor valued by the school system. What sort of a system is it that wastes these talents, that sends four-fifths of its students away with a permanent stigma in the eyes of society’s gatekeepers, and perhaps in their own eyes as well? Are the dubious benefits of the privileges and opportunities accorded a presumed “analytical intelligence elite” by this pedagogical tunnel vision worth so much social damage and waste?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food for thought.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">James C. Scott “Two Cheers for Anarchism”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Khanlabschool</title><link href="/2019/07/13/khanlabschool.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Khanlabschool" /><published>2019-07-13T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/13/khanlabschool</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/13/khanlabschool.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;salman-khan-rethinks-school&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://khanlabschool.org/wired&quot;&gt;Salman Khan Rethinks School&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My second post today on education and pedagogy. This article is a fairly old piece, but it is nonetheless a good read. I also recommend the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/sal_khan_let_s_teach_for_mastery_not_test_scores?language=en&quot;&gt;10-minute video available on TED&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Salman Khan Rethinks School</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Newmacbooks</title><link href="/2019/07/09/newmacbooks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Newmacbooks" /><published>2019-07-09T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-09T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/09/newmacbooks</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/09/newmacbooks.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;apple-adjusts-entry-level-macbook-configurations&quot;&gt;Apple Adjusts Entry-Level MacBook Configurations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple has quietly adjusted its mid-2019 lineup for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/mac/&quot;&gt;MacBook, MacBook Air, and MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 12-inch MacBook with Retina display is no longer for sale. This shouldn’t be to a surprise to anyone. The 11-inch and 12.9-inch iPad Pro does a much better job of being an ultraportable, ultrafast device at a similar price point. Realistically speaking, the 12-inch MacBook was doomed as soon as Intel abandoned its plans to further develop competitive sub 5w and 3w mobile processors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 13-inch MacBook Air is now the entry-level MacBook, available from just US$999 (with student discount). This should’ve happened from launch day, but I suppose it’s better late than never. Its Retina display now comes with True Tone technology too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 13-inch MacBook Pro with two Thunderbolt 3 ports and &lt;strong&gt;no&lt;/strong&gt; Touch Bar – dubbed the MacBook Escape by Apple fans – is no longer available. Again, this should’ve happened with the launch of 2018 MacBook Air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new 13-inch MacBook Pro with Touch Bar and two Thunderbolt 3 ports is now available from US$1,299. This means that &lt;strong&gt;every&lt;/strong&gt; MacBook Pro now comes with Touch ID and the Touch Bar. Hallelujah, we finally have some consistency across the MacBook Pro lineup!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of these changes should’ve happened a long time ago, but perhaps were delayed or deferred until Apple could hit sufficient manufacturing yields and margins.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
Unfortunately, the entire MacBook lineup still features Apple’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/keyboard-service-program-for-mac-notebooks&quot;&gt;much maligned butterfly keyboards&lt;/a&gt;, so we’ll have to wait a little while longer to get new keyboards. I expect this to happen either the end of this year, or early next year when Apple moves to a new chassis across its MacBook lineups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, we should focus on the positives of today’s shuffling: the MacBook lineup finally makes some damn sense. Students and people who want portable macOS should aim for the MacBook Air, working professionals take the 13-inch MacBook Pro, and content creators and developers can claim the 15-inch MacBook Pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following updates to the iMac, Mac mini, and Mac Pro, 2019 is shaping up to be a great year for the Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit&lt;/em&gt;: HomePod is &lt;strong&gt;finally&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/jp/homepod/&quot;&gt;available in Japan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news for the Mac doesn’t end. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrumors.com/2019/07/09/storage-upgrades-price-drop/&quot;&gt;As reported by MacRumors&lt;/a&gt;, Apple has cut the price of flash storage upgrades across its entire Mac lineup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The views expressed here are purely my own, and do not reflect the views or opinions of Apple. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Apple Adjusts Entry-Level MacBook Configurations</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hkairdrop</title><link href="/2019/07/09/hkairdrop.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hkairdrop" /><published>2019-07-09T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-09T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/09/hkairdrop</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/09/hkairdrop.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;hong-kong-protestors-use-airdrop-brilliantly&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1660460/hong-kong-protesters-use-airdrop-to-breach-chinas-firewall/&quot;&gt;Hong Kong Protestors use AirDrop Brilliantly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mary Hui at Quarz:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hong Kong’s protesters are using AirDrop, a file-sharing feature that allows Apple devices to send photos and videos over Bluetooth and Wi-Fi, to breach China’s Great Firewall in order to spread information to mainland Chinese visitors in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What an amazing way to avoid the Great Firewall of China, and to spread information in a peaceful way toward their cause. I continue to be impressed and moved by what’s happening in Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continue to hope that the Hong Kong people achieve further independence, and to protect their democratic rights and freedoms.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hong Kong Protestors use AirDrop Brilliantly Mary Hui at Quarz:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Isaacasimov</title><link href="/2019/07/08/isaacasimov.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Isaacasimov" /><published>2019-07-08T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-08T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/08/isaacasimov</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/08/isaacasimov.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;isaac-asimov&quot;&gt;Isaac Asimov&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A beautiful quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;However, I continue to try and I continue, indefatigably, to reach out. There’s no way I can single handedly save the world or, perhaps, even make a perceptible difference—but how ashamed I would be to let a day pass without making one more effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Isaac Asimov</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mylai</title><link href="/2019/07/08/mylai.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mylai" /><published>2019-07-08T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-08T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/08/mylai</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/08/mylai.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-my-lai-massacre&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2018/03/my-lai-50/555671/?utm_campaign=the-atlantic&amp;amp;utm_content=5c8d2bac4b73850001c4b878_ta&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=facebook&amp;amp;fbclid=IwAR0Qw9VMKkhN49tMQXO2x15SKCjlhjutxMwXpQJPmBQR_0Yp7LzmgeqJfzM&quot;&gt;The My Lai Massacre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From The Atlantic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s hard to fathom how a group of young American men, most of whom would never have killed anyone but for the Vietnam War, spiralled out of control together, perpetrating atrocities that rival any committed in the annals of human warfare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And yet, whenever a country’s civilian leaders decide to send young men to fight any war of sustained length, it is almost certain that discipline will break down somewhere, that savagery will take hold sometime, and that shameful evil will be done, as had happened during the Civil War, World War I, World War II, and the Korean War.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The My Lai Massacre</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Xiaomicopies</title><link href="/2019/07/06/xiaomicopies.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Xiaomicopies" /><published>2019-07-06T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-06T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/06/xiaomicopies</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/06/xiaomicopies.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;xiaomi-copies-apple-again&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.caixinglobal.com/2019-07-05/xiaomi-accidentally-uses-apple-video-to-advertise-controversial-mimoji-phone-101436026.html&quot;&gt;Xiaomi Copies Apple… Again&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I originally saw this on John Gruber’s Daring Fireball, but I had to share it here because it’s just another classic example of Chinese-based smartphone companies blatantly ripping off and copying Apple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the closest real-life example we can get of the homework meme.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Xiaomi Copies Apple… Again</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Japansbiggestproblem</title><link href="/2019/07/05/japansbiggestproblem.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Japansbiggestproblem" /><published>2019-07-05T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-05T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/05/japansbiggestproblem</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/05/japansbiggestproblem.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;japans-single-greatest-challenge&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.japantimes.co.jp/news/2019/07/02/national/social-issues/japans-gender-problem-human-disaster-says-award-winning-scholar-chizuko-ueno/#.XR4bMy1L3UI&quot;&gt;Japan’s Single Greatest Challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fantastic piece from The Japan Times, providing a spotlight on Professor Chizuko Ueno and her continuing fight for gender equality in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professor Ueno gave a fantastic speech to this year’s graduate intake at The University of Tokyo, reminding the students not to succumb to ivory tower syndrome, and to raise awareness on the single biggest plague and infection in Japanese society, misogyny:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“There are people whose drive is dampened even before they try because of negative comments or thoughts like ‘You won’t succeed no matter what’ or ‘After all, nobody believes in me,’ ” she said. “I hope you won’t focus your efforts only to win the game for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I hope you will use your gifted talents and favorable environment to help those who are less fortunate, and do not denigrate them. And I hope you live your life by accepting who you are even with your weaknesses and by helping and supporting each other,”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The 70-year-old scholar, who is also a chief director of the nonprofit Women’s Action Network, pointed out that less than 20 percent of students entering the University of Tokyo, better known as Todai, are female. This is despite there being plentiful evidence that female applicants have higher standard scores than their male competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People often ask me what I think Japan’s greatest crisis is: China and the US, North Korea, rapidly ageing demographics, or maybe deflation and slow GDP growth? No. It’s the blatant double standards and the glass ceiling that women across Japan have to face on a constant basis. Don’t even get me started on the large social costs that this incurs – if we just focus on the economic costs, how many Nobel Prizes, breakthroughs in science and technology, and seismic productivity improvements has Japan lost by failing to ensure an equality of opportunity to the millions of highly intelligent women in this country?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all of Japan’s obsessions with gaining equal footing with the West from an economic, political, and cultural point of view, it will forever be relegated as second-class so long as women here are treated here as second-class.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Japan’s Single Greatest Challenge</summary></entry></feed>