<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-05T00:48:19+09:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Alabamalawapp</title><link href="/2019/07/05/alabamalawapp.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alabamalawapp" /><published>2019-07-05T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-05T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/05/alabamalawapp</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/05/alabamalawapp.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;alabama-abortion-and-insane-law-applications&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/03/us/charges-dropped-alabama-woman-pregnant.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=Top+Stories&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&amp;amp;fbclid=IwAR3P6lvCmH_TCioufgEmV9Xer4EN55buLLNJ-oK1xfyg9mKwTcZRomkpKqg&quot;&gt;Alabama, Abortion, and Insane Law Applications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now, you’ve probably already heard about Alabama’s controversial abortion laws, and the absolutely mind boggling case of Marshae Jones. From the New York Times article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Marshae Jones, was accused of beating up a co-worker who ultimately drew a gun and fired it, wounding Ms. Jones in the stomach and killing her five-month-old fetus. A grand jury in Jefferson County, convened by District Attorney Lynneice Washington, dismissed charges against the co-worker, saying she had acted in self-defense. But it indicted Ms. Jones for “initiating a fight knowing she was five months pregnant.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Under Alabama law, a fetus is considered to have the same rights as a child who has already been born. The grand jury sought to hold someone accountable for its death and Ms. Jones was arrested last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After drawing wide spread criticism, and becoming top news in the US, prosecutors announced on Wednesday that they would be dropping the manslaughter charges &lt;strong&gt;against Ms Jones&lt;/strong&gt;. The fact that the law was applied in this way, such that a grand jury decided that Ms Jones be held accountable for the loss of her unborn baby, is absolutely insane. I’m legitimately baffled at this entire case, and have to remind myself that this is taking place in the US.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Alabama, Abortion, and Insane Law Applications</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Japansbiggestproblem</title><link href="/2019/07/05/japansbiggestproblem.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Japansbiggestproblem" /><published>2019-07-05T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-05T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/05/japansbiggestproblem</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/05/japansbiggestproblem.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;japans-single-greatest-challenge&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.japantimes.co.jp/news/2019/07/02/national/social-issues/japans-gender-problem-human-disaster-says-award-winning-scholar-chizuko-ueno/#.XR4bMy1L3UI&quot;&gt;Japan’s Single Greatest Challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fantastic piece from The Japan Times, providing a spotlight on Professor Chizuko Ueno and her continuing fight for gender equality in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professor Ueno gave a fantastic speech to this year’s graduate intake at The University of Tokyo, reminding the students not to succumb to ivory tower syndrome, and to raise awareness on the single biggest plague and infection in Japanese society, misogyny:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“There are people whose drive is dampened even before they try because of negative comments or thoughts like ‘You won’t succeed no matter what’ or ‘After all, nobody believes in me,’ ” she said. “I hope you won’t focus your efforts only to win the game for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I hope you will use your gifted talents and favorable environment to help those who are less fortunate, and do not denigrate them. And I hope you live your life by accepting who you are even with your weaknesses and by helping and supporting each other,”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The 70-year-old scholar, who is also a chief director of the nonprofit Women’s Action Network, pointed out that less than 20 percent of students entering the University of Tokyo, better known as Todai, are female. This is despite there being plentiful evidence that female applicants have higher standard scores than their male competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People often ask me what I think Japan’s greatest crisis is: China and the US, North Korea, rapidly ageing demographics, or maybe deflation and slow GDP growth? No. It’s the blatant double standards and the glass ceiling that women across Japan have to face on a constant basis. Don’t even get me started on the large social costs that this incurs – if we just focus on the economic costs, how many Nobel Prizes, breakthroughs in science and technology, and seismic productivity improvements has Japan lost by failing to ensure an equality of opportunity to the millions of highly intelligent women in this country?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all of Japan’s obsessions with gaining equal footing with the West from an economic, political, and cultural point of view, it will forever be relegated as second-class so long as women here are treated here as second-class.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Japan’s Single Greatest Challenge</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Taxcutsforwhom</title><link href="/2019/07/02/taxcutsforwhom.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taxcutsforwhom" /><published>2019-07-02T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-02T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/07/02/taxcutsforwhom</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/07/02/taxcutsforwhom.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;tax-cuts-for-whom&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/701424?fbclid=IwAR3INhQR8CBX_IxamQYb_Y2ZyusCHzwfBw4L9GcEdMVFb8K9GI7lY1YaAoU&quot;&gt;Tax Cuts for Whom?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interesting paper from Owen Zidar (Princeton and the NBER) on the links between income tax cuts and economic activity:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I find that the positive relationship between tax cuts and employment growth is largely driven by tax cuts for lower-income groups and that the effect of tax cuts for the top 10 percent on employment growth is small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nut shell, trickle down economics is rubbish.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Tax Cuts for Whom?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Helloworld</title><link href="/2019/06/30/helloworld.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Helloworld" /><published>2019-06-30T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-06-30T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>/2019/06/30/helloworld</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/06/30/helloworld.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;hello-world&quot;&gt;Hello World&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site has been a long time coming. With the help of my friend, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/yuki-robson-176396a4/&quot;&gt;Yuki Robson&lt;/a&gt;, I finally have somewhere to share my thoughts, opinions, and rants.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hello World</summary></entry></feed>